A Guide to the Lancaster County (Va.) Records, 1703-1918
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Lancaster County (Va.) Records, 1703-1918
The Library of Virginia
50291
7.00 cu. ft. (16 boxes and 1 vol.)
Lancaster County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These items came to the Library of Virginia in a transfer of court papers from Lancaster County under the accession number 50291.
Historical Information
Lancaster County was named for the English county. It was formed from Northumberland and York Counties in 1651.
Scope and Content
Lancaster County (Va.) Records, 1703-1918, consist of Bonds/Commissions Oaths (1860-1865); Overseer of the Poor records (1870-1877); court records including commonwealth causes and other criminal records (1889-1896 circa), chancery causes (1918), and judgments (1861-1898 circa); election records (1852-1918 circa) which includes lists of colored and white voters, 1867; deeds (1874-1900 circa); plats (1811-1950); fiduciary records (1886-1900 circa); and tax and fiscal records (1853-1898 circa ) including a Sheriff's Tax Book (1853-1856). Several boxes include a wide array of records including fiduciary records, board of supervisor records, bonds, jury records, organization records, public buildings and grounds records, and road and bridge records.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Lancaster County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Subjects:
Public records -- Virginia -- Lancaster County.
Geographical Names:
Lancaster County (Va.) -- History.
Genre and Form Terms:
Bonds (legal records) -- Virginia -- Lancaster County.; Chancery causes -- Virginia -- Lancaster County.; Civil court cases -- Virginia -- Lancaster County.; County government records -- Virginia -- Lancaster County.; Criminal court records -- Virginia -- Lancaster County.; Deeds -- Virginia -- Lancaster County.; Fiduciary records -- Virginia -- Lancaster County.; Local government records -- Virginia -- Lancaster County.; Plats -- Virginia -- Lancaster County.; Tax records -- Virginia -- Lancaster County.
Contents List
- Records, 1867-1900 circa.
  Contains deeds, fiduciary records,and processioners reports.
- Records, 1867-1918 circa.
  Contains deeds, judgments, fiduciary records, chancery cause (1918), and election records including lists of colored and white voters, 1867.
- Judgments, 1861-1898 circa
- Commonwealth causes, 1889-1896
- Deeds, 1874-1896 circa
- Bonds/Commissions/Oaths, 1860-1865
- Election Records: Polls, 1852-1861 circa
- Overseer of the Poor Records, 1870-1877
- Tax and Fiscal Records, 1860-1898 circa
- Tax and Fiscal Records: Sheriff's tax book, 1853-1856
- Court Records, 1703-1899.
  Contains Board of Supervisors: Records related to the poor house (1809, 1897-1899); Bonds/Commissions/Oaths: officials' commissions (1777-1849); Bonds/Commissions/Oaths: various bonds (1703-1721); Court Records: Criminal (1892-1893); Court Records: receipt for payment of a debt, Leland vs. George (1805); Fiduciary Records: administrators' bonds (1712-1726); Land Records: deeds (1868-1869, 1890); Organization Records: Hopewell Church, Methodist Episcopal Church South copy of document put into church cornerstone (1876); Public Buildings and Grounds: building committee for erection of new courthouse (1859); Road and Bridge Records: order for a change of road (1849).
- Court Records, 1840-1896.
  Includes deeds, account of sales, oaths of allegiance, guardianship papers, estate appraisements, guardian accounts, Board of Supervisors (1896), jury records (1896), constable's bond (1896), and various court papers (1864 and 1867).
- Plats 1811-1950; undated